# KEVIN (CHANH P.), NGO

N Lincoln Ave, Monterey Park, CA - 91755 · (+1) 626 877 3058 pngo19@calstatela.edu · https://www.linkedin.com/in/fkvn/ · https://github.com/fkvn

By picturing myself as a Full-Stack developer and concerning my long-term goals, I want to be an expert on the website development field, especially of progressive Web Applications, which predictably become the major competitor to mobile apps in the modern age.

Besides, people who I've worked with are always willing to write a recommendation letter for me and give me a positive performance review. I'm proud to say that my secure communication, outstanding attitude, and impressive leadership skills set me apart from other programmers.

#### **EDUCATION**

08/2018 - PRESENT

M.S., COMPUTER SCIENCE, CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, LOS ANGELES

GPA: 4.0

1/2017 - 5/2018

**ENGLISH STUDIES, CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, LONG BEACH (ALI)** 

GPA: 4.0

8/2011 - 4/2016

B.S., COMPUTER SCIENCE, HO CHI MINH CITY, UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY

GPA: 3.1

#### SKILLS

#### **BACK-END WEB DEVELOPMENT**

- Spring boot (REST API)
- Node.js / Express.JS (REST API)
- MongoDB
- MySQL

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE

- Java
- JavaScript
- Python
- C#

#### **ADDITIONAL SKILL**

- Leadership, collaboration, teamwork, planning.
- Adaptability, critical thinking, problem solving.

#### FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPMENT

- HTML / CSS / JavaScript
- React.js
- React Bootstrap / Redux
- Vue.js

#### TECHNOLOGY/SOFWARE/TOOL

- Data Science + Machine Learning
- Git + GitHub
- Eclipse
- Vs code

#### **PROJECTS**

(https://github.com/fkvn?tab=repositories)

#### HIRING PROCESS SERVICE

Developed Rest API backend with Spring Boot application to build a hiring process service as a standalone service which can be integrated into another system via a Rest API.

Implemented in: Java, Maven, Spring-Boot, My SQL, REST API.

**Details**: <a href="https://github.com/fkvn/hiring-service-restapi">https://github.com/fkvn/hiring-service-restapi</a>

#### POS SYSTEM SERVICE

The goal of the project is to develop a server-side API service to facilitate the management process for a small-medium coffee shop. Owners can track hours, communicate with employees, and perform other tasks that help their store run smoothly.

Implemented in: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, REST API.

**Details**: <a href="https://github.com/fkvn/pos-system-service-restapi">https://github.com/fkvn/pos-system-service-restapi</a>

#### **SURVEY SERVICE**

The ability to conduct surveys is a requirement for many systems, e.g. political campaigns, marketing research, and program assessment. The main purpose is to build a survey service which to be reused in another system (especially another system written in a different programming language) as a standalone service.

Implemented in: Java, Maven, Spring-Boot, My SQL, REST API.

**Details**: https://github.com/fkvn/survey-service-restapi

#### **EXPERIENCE**

10/2018 - PRESENT

#### **ASSISTANT LAB CONSULTANT,** CAL STATE LA – ITS (IT CLIENT SUPPORT SERVICES)

Attend customer service and keep updated on ITS services available for campus users. One of the most challenging things is maintaining lab services for software, security, and helping students most appropriately. In addition to my tech-savvy skills, I devote particular emphasis to punctuality, handling under pressure, and maintaining outstanding performance.

7/2014 – 10/2014

#### **DEVELOPER INTERN, ISB VIETNAM COMPANY LIMITED (IVC)**

Communicated with the supervisor to implement multiple tasks related, mainly, to Visual Basic for Application (VBA) for Microsoft Excel. Primarily working on analyzing, researching, and implementing data from excel files to export expected results in terms of business/client demand.

#### **ACTIVITIES**

#### CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, LOS ANGELES

Cal State LA MESA Prelims 2019.

Regional Middle School Science Bowl (RSB) from the U.S.

130<sup>th</sup> annual Rose Parade celebration – Rose Parade Float Decorating.

ECST Open House in Partnership with Boeing Training Dates.

#### CALIFORNIA STATE UNIVERSITY, LONG BEACH.

Student Ambassador.
CSULB Phi Delta Conference.

## **LANGUAGES**

VIETNAMESE ENGLISH CHINESE

Native or Bilingual Full Professional Limited Working

### **LICENSES & CERTIFICATIONS**

LinkedIn

**BECOME A SPRING DEVELOPER** 

Issued 2020.

LinkedIn

**BECOME A MEARN STACK JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER** 

Issued 2020.

LinkedIn

**BECOME A VUE.JS DEVELOPER** 

Issued 2020.

LinkedIn

**MYSQL ESSENTIAL TRAINING** 

Issued 2020.

# REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST